{
 "subject": "geography",
 "lesson": "l01",
 "grade": "c8",
 "quests": [
	{
		"id": 1,
		"question": "Which of the following is known as sphere of rocks.",
		"options": {
			"a": "Atmosphere",
			"b": "Biosphere",
			"c": "Lithosphere",
			"d": "Hydrosphere"
		},
		"answer": "c"
	},
	{
		"id": 2,
		"question": "World soil day is observed on",
		"options": {
			"a": "15th August",
			"b": "12th January",
			"c": "15th October",
			"d": "5th December"
		},
		"answer": "d"
	},
	{
		"id": 3,
		"question": "Fossils are found in",
		"options": {
			"a": "Sedimentary rocks",
			"b": "Igneous rocks",
			"c": "Metamorphic rocks",
			"d": "Plutonic rocks"
		},
		"answer": "a"
	},
	{
		"id": 4,
		"question": "The top layer of soil is called as",
		"options": {
			"a": "organic layer or humas",
			"b": "topsoil",
			"c": "subsoil",
			"d": "bedrock"
		},
		"answer": "b"
	},
	{
		"id": 5,
		"question": "Ideal soil for growing cotton is",
		"options": {
			"a": "Red soil",
			"b": "Black soil",
			"c": "Alluvial soil",
			"d": "Mountain soil"
		},
		"answer": "b"
	},
	{
		"id": 6,
		"question": "The major components of soil is.",
		"options": {
			"a": "Rocks",
			"b": "Minerals",
			"c": "Water",
			"d": "All the above"
		},
		"answer": "b"
	},
	{
		"id": 7,
		"question": "Which one of the following is the most widespread most and productive category of soil?",
		"options": {
			"a": "Alluvial soil",
			"b": "Black soil",
			"c": "Red soil",
			"d": "Mountain soil"
		},
		"answer": "a"
	},
	{
		"id": 8,
		"question": "Basalt",
		"options": {
			"a": "Anthracite",
			"b": "Extrusive igneous",
			"c": "Metamorphic rock",
			"d": "Sedimentary rock"
		},
		"answer": "b"
	},
	{
		"id": 9,
		"question": "Limestone",
		"options": {
			"a": "Anthracite",
			"b": "Extrusive igneous",
			"c": "Metamorphic rock",
			"d": "Sedimentary rock"
		},
		"answer": "d"
	},
	{
		"id": 10,
		"question": "Coal",
		"options": {
			"a": "Anthracite",
			"b": "Extrusive igneous",
			"c": "Metamorphic rock",
			"d": "Sedimentary rock"
		},
		"answer": "a"
	},
	{
		"id": 11,
		"question": "Gneiss",
		"options": {
			"a": "Anthracite",
			"b": "Extrusive igneous",
			"c": "Metamorphic rock",
			"d": "Sedimentary rock"
		},
		"answer": "c"
	},
	{
		"id": 12,
		"question": "Igneous rocks are called primary rocks.",
		"options": {
			"a": "True",
			"b": "False",
			"c": "",
			"d": ""
		},
		"answer": "a"
	},
	{
		"id": 13,
		"question": "Slate is formed from shale.",
		"options": {
			"a": "True",
			"b": "False",
			"c": "",
			"d": ""
		},
		"answer": "a"
	},
	{
		"id": 14,
		"question": "Red soil is formed by the process of leaching..",
		"options": {
			"a": "True",
			"b": "False",
			"c": "",
			"d": ""
		},
		"answer": "b"
	},
	{
		"id": 15,
		"question": "M-sand is used as alternative for natural sand in construction.",
		"options": {
			"a": "True",
			"b": "False",
			"c": "",
			"d": ""
		},
		"answer": "a"
	},
	{
		"id": 16,
		"question": "Volcanic mountains are covered with sedimentary rocks.",
		"options": {
			"a": "True",
			"b": "False",
			"c": "",
			"d": ""
		},
		"answer": "b"
	},
	{
		"id": 17,
		"question": "Granite",
		"options": {
			"a": "Bed rock",
			"b": "Plutonic rock",
			"c": "Strip farming",
			"d": "Active Volcano"
		},
		"answer": "b"
	},
	{
		"id": 18,
		"question": "Soil layer",
		"options": {
			"a": "Bed rock",
			"b": "Plutonic rock",
			"c": "Strip farming",
			"d": "Active Volcano"
		},
		"answer": "a"
	},
	{
		"id": 19,
		"question": "Barren island",
		"options": {
			"a": "Bed rock",
			"b": "Plutonic rock",
			"c": "Strip farming",
			"d": "Active Volcano"
		},
		"answer": "d"
	},
	{
		"id": 20,
		"question": "Soil conservation",
		"options": {
			"a": "Bed rock",
			"b": "Plutonic rock",
			"c": "Strip farming",
			"d": "Active Volcano"
		},
		"answer": "c"
	}
  ]
}